Wie hat der 7. Oktober dein Gefühl von Sicherheit
verändert – und das, was Heimat und Zugehörigkeit
für Dich bedeutet?
That is a very
profound question...
I will share something very personal,
I started getting, many people
started getting help,
psychological help...
after October 7 to deal with the trauma.
And I remember one day that I was sitting with my...
Psychologist...
and I wanted to speak about my house in Nahal Oz,
and the words I used were "the building in Nahal Oz",
and once I said that sentence,
I was like...
It was just then,
that I realized that I feel very detached,
from my house now.
Nahal Oz is a place that...
We've been through quite a lot here,
we had many difficult incidents throughout the years,
when people say it didn’t start on October 7,
they are right,
it didn’t start on October 7,
we had many difficult incidents here,
throughout the years...
including...
a yellow school bus that was targeted by a...
laser-guided anti-tank missile including.
A four-and-a-half year old child that died here,
from a sharp nail that entered his house.
Including many things throughout the years,
and, I've never wanted to leave.
Never...
I always said that I will stay here no matter what...
because of the story of my family.
Are we getting there later?
Okay,
so I will touch it a little bit...
After a terrible incident happened...
I used to think about my family,
my family...
I'm Middle Eastern to the backbone,
Middle Eastern,
North African. I'm from the region,
I couldn’t be imperialist even if I wanted to...
And, I always say that...
I'm the first indigenous imperialist known to mankind...
and, I've got nowhere to go.
Nobody is doing me a favor and letting me leave,
in the Middle East,
I couldn’t be in Paris this year,
I couldn’t...
Now if you want to open the world map,
and show us where our haven is,
it would be fantastic.
People around the world,
that tell us to go back to Europe,
I come from Libya,
it’s a bit problematic...
And, my family was terrorized throughout the years.
I'm second generation to refugees from...
My mom is a refugee from Libya,
she was terrorized out as a child with her family,
And when that thought crossed my mind,
when things happened around here,
I said maybe I will be that link in the chain,
that did not submit to terror,
that did not...
move around because she was terrorized...
And, October 7 broke that...
I think that...
October 7 was the first time that I realized,
it took me about a couple of weeks,
after all the stories gathered,
because we were in our safe rooms,
we didn’t know what was going on in all the other
locations around us so...
when the stories started gathering in...
and we heard the horrible stories about...
mutilations and...
horrible rapes and brutal
murders...
There was one Thai worker...
that was here for quite a while...
they killed him with a shovel...
a few meters from my house,
this is something that you can’t even...
you can’t digest something like that...
It’s very difficult to...
So I think that...
it took me about a couple of weeks to realize that...
just like my mom,
I survived a massacre in the Middle East.
And, I think that it was the first time,
that the level of terror
got to the level of terror that they used to face,
back in Libya...
or here in the region of Israel,
where my father's family was,
for years and years and years,
in Hebron, Gaza...
Jerusalem.
My father,
as a child went through the siege in Jerusalem.
They're here for generations on generations
on generations...
I thought that I would be that link in the chain,
submit to terror and today I'm not that sure...
I still think about...
coming back here or not,
my family really wants to come back,
my son...
is afraid about it. I have a handicapped son,
he can not run for shelter
in a few seconds.
So for now...
we’re out of the kibbutz for another year,
and we'll see what happens then...